Guide to the John Trumbull Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PERSONAL AND FAMILY PAPERS, 1750-1896, undated; Series III; .75 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - Trumbull, David's family (Joseph, John M., and Jonathan G.W. Trumbull), 1817-1844 (Box 7, Folder 113, Reel 5U)
    See also: box 7, folder 107 box 16, folder 154
  - Trumbull, James, undated (Box 7, Folder 114, Reel 5U)
  - Trumbull, John (1750-1831): letter of William M. Holland to Park Benjamin concerning, 1836 (Box 7, Folder 115, Reel 5U)
  - Trumbull, Jonathan (1710-1785), 1750-1783, undated (Box 7, Folder 116, Reel 5U)
  - Trumbull, Jonathan (1740-1809)
    - General, 1763-1805, undated (Box 7, Folder 117, Reel 5U)
    - Journal, 1764-1773 (Box 8, Folder 118-119, Reel 6U)
    - Ledger, 1767-1808 (Box 8, Folder 120, Reel 6U)
    - Loose papers found in ledgers, 1767-1801, undated (Box 9, Folder 121, Reel 6U)
  - Trumbull, Joseph (1737-1778) (Box 9, Folder 122, Reel 6U)
    See also: box 16, folder 154
  - Trumbull, Sarah Hope (Harvey), 1799, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 123, Reel 6U)
  - Wadsworth, Faith (Trumbull): diary (1803-1846) in commonplace book "Miscellania Juvenilis-Johannis Trumbull" (1779), 1779, 1803-1846 (Box 9, Folder 124, Reel 6U)
  - Wadsworth, Harriet, 1781-1792 (Box 9, Folder 125, Reel 6U)
  - Genealogical and biographical notes and charts, undated (Box 9, Folder 126, Reel 6U)
    See also: box 7, folder 100 box 16, folder 154
  - Unidentified, 1793-1896, undated (Box 9, Folder 127, Reel 6U)
- THEODORE SIZER'S FILES, 1773-1961, undated; Series IV; 2.25 linear feet (6 boxes)
  This series includes material bound into volumes and material stored loose in file folders. The bound volumes are arranged at the beginning of the series and are listed in alphabetical order according to the cover title. Two untitled volumes are listed afterwards as topical files. The loose material is organized by record type and the files are listed in alphabetical order.
  - Benjamin Silliman's Note Book, 1858, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 128, Reel 7U)
  - Col. John Trumbull: The When, Where & What Book, undated (Box 10, Folder 129, Reel 7U)
  - Trumbull's Autobiography with Supplementary Notes, Circa 1851-1951 (Box 10, Folder 130, Reel 7U)
  - Trumbull's Autobiography with Supplementary Notes, Circa 1851-1951 (Box 11, Folder 131, Reel 8U)
  - Miscellaneous Trumbull Papers: Curator's Copy, Circa 1926-1950 (Box 12, Folder 132, Reel 8U)
  - Miscellaneous Trumbull Papers: Office Copy, Circa 1926-1951 (Box 12, Folder 133, Reel 8U)
  - Col. John Trumbull: His Work Arranged in Chronological Sequence, undated (Box 12, Folder 134, Reel 8U)
  - Col. John Trumbull: His Work Arranged by Location, undated (Box 13, Folder 135, Reel 9U)
  - Topical files, circa 1901-1948, circa 1930-1951 (Box 13, Folder 136-137, Reel 9U)
  - Correspondence concerning the location of Trumbull documents, 1872-1957 (Box 13, Folder 138, Reel 9U)
  - Documents: lists of those microfilmed or in Hartford, 1924, undated (Box 13, Folder 139, Reel 9U)
  - Documents: unsorted copies and notes, 1773-1879, undated (Box 13, Folder 140, Reel 9U)
  - Printed matter: catalogues of Trumbull's paintings and papers, 1864-1897 (Box 14, Folder 141, Reel 9U)
  - Printed matter: catalogues of Trumbull's paintings and papers, 1926-1938, undated (Box 14, Folder 142, Reel 9U)
  - Printed matter: writings of others on Trumbull, 1833-1931, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 143-144, Reel 9U)
  - Writings by Sizer, Circa 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 145, Reel 9U)
  - Writings by Sizer: "A Tentative 'Short-Title' Checklist of the Works of Col. John Trumbull", 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 146, Reel 9U)
  - Writings by Sizer, Circa 1948-1952 (Box 15, Folder 147, Reel 10U)
  - Writings by Sizer: "The American Academy of Fine Arts, New York City, 1802-1840", 1951-1953 (Box 15, Folder 148, Reel 10U)
  - Writings by Sizer, 1956-1961 (Box 15, Folder 149, Reel 10U)
- OVERSIZE
  - Correspondence, 1776, 1780 (Box 16, Folder 150, Reel 10U)
  - Business papers from folders 55-90, 1777, 1780, 1795-1798, undated (Box 16, Folder 151, Reel 10U)
  - Business papers from folder 91, 1796-1797 (Box 16, Folder 152, Reel 10U)
  - Family papers: John Trumbull, 1786, 1809, 1828, 1831 (Box 16, Folder 153, Reel 10U)
  - Family papers: other family members, 1776-1782, 1842, undated (Box 16, Folder 154, Reel 10U)
- COPY NEGATIVES
  - From box 2, folder 31 (Box 17)
    Reel No: Not on film
  - From box 4, folder 60 (Box 17)